# Stephen Burns /// Junior Software Engineer

Telluride, Colorado

(720) 436-4597

stephenburns272@gmail.com

LinkedIn | GitHub

I am a recent graduate with a Bachelors of Science in Computer Science. I am proficient in Java, with experience working with SQL and C++. My experience as a mountain guide as well as working with video editing for a documentary film festival have steered my focus on industries that better the human experience. I aim to translate this passion towards one more specific to technology and integration into people's everyday lives.

# **SKILLS**

Java, SQL, C++, JavaScript, AndroidStudio, VSCode, Google Workspace Tools, Premiere Pro

# **EXPERIENCE**

Playa Bike Repair, Remote, 2022 /// Software Engineering Intern, Data Entry Automation

- Automated process to collect and store customer data for eCommerce bicycle rental business to coordinate time-sensitive logistics for delivery and pickup of both individual orders and large group orders of bicycle rentals
- Configured Apps Script and Google Sheets to automate creation of customized emails in mass email campaign to
  collect customer data, then manually analyzed and organized the customer input received from email campaign to
  coordinate product delivery

CSU Global, 2020-2022 /// Bachelors Degree in Computer Science

### **Selected School Projects:**

#### **HOME ENERGY AUDIT APPLICATION:** Android App for Determining Home Energy Usage

- Built an application in Java that determines home energy usage based on the user's location and local utility rates, and type and quantity of appliances in home
- Created local database asset that housed typical energy outputs for standard large household appliances, and performed
  parameterized SQL queries based on user input to determine energy consumption. Calculated total estimated energy costs
  by then performing API calls to the National Renewable Energy Lab database to obtain local utility rates.

# **PET FEEDER APPLICATION:** Android App for Theoretical Product

 Created an Android Application for a theoretical automated pet feeder utilizing a SQLite database, widgets, activities, and fragments.

MountainTrip, Telluride, CO, 2016 - present /// Professional Mountain & Climbing Guide,

 Lead clients on high angle technical mountain climbing excursions, typically involving thorough communication of tasks at hand, risks, and mitigation of risks. This role requires excellent time management, risk assessment, & customer service skills.

Certifications: NOLS Wilderness First Responder, AMGA Certified Climbing Guide

MountainFilm, Telluride, CO, 2013 - 2022 /// Tour Production Coordinator & Tour Representative

- Created and edited custom documentary film festival playlists and content using Airtable to navigate workflows
- Managed and configured dedicated RAID and NAS systems for company wide access and data backups
- Traveled nationally & internationally as a film festival tour emcee, stage manager, and media coordinator

# Alley Cat Cafe, Fort Collins, CO, 2006-2012 /// Cafe Manager

Managed busy 24 hour cafe

#### Colorado VNet, Loveland, CO, 2005-2006 /// Quality Assurance Specialist

- Conducted QA testing for digital home audio and lighting systems.
- Constructed and wired home audio integration systems for testing and tradeshows.

# **EDUCATION**

Colorado State University Global, Aurora, CO / Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, 2022, Magna Cum Laude